{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Swirling and vortex formation can be prevented by", "opta": "using baffles", "optb": "using diffusion ring with turbines", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Power number is expressed as", "opta": "P0 / N2Di3\u03c1", "optb": "P0 / N3Di5\u03c1", "optc": "P0 / N3Di3\u03c1", "optd": "P0 / N2Di2\u03c1", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The power consumption in a stirring vessel can be assessed by using a", "opta": "dynamometer", "optb": "strain gauge attached to agitator shaft", "optc": "watt meter attached to agitator motor", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Surface renewal theory predicts that the mass transfer coefficient is", "opta": "directly proportional to the square root of the molecular diffusivity", "optb": "inversely proportional to the square root of the molecular diffusivity", "optc": "directly proportional to the cube root of the molecular diffusivity", "optd": "indirectly proportional to the cube root of the molecular diffusivity", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The oxygen transfer rate in a bioreactor will increase if", "opta": "oil is added", "optb": "antifoam is added", "optc": "detergent like molecules are added", "optd": "increase in the reactor temperature", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following impellers are used for wide range of viscosities?", "opta": "paddles", "optb": "turbines", "optc": "propellers", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following type(s) of stirrer can be used for microbiological processes?", "opta": "Mig", "optb": "Intermig", "optc": "Turbine", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The range of width for the baffle in the fermenter is __________ times of vessel diameter", "opta": "1/10 to 1/12", "optb": "1/8 to 1/10", "optc": "1/5 to 1/8", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The average concentration of oxygen in the boundary layers surrounding the bubbles (Co*) in a reactor is normally determined by", "opta": "ultra-small dissolved oxygen probes", "optb": "laser based photographic systems", "optc": "measuring the steady state concentration of oxygen in the bulk liquid prior to inoculation of the reactor", "optd": "measuring the steady state concentration of oxygen in the bulk liquid after inoculation of the reactor", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why vortexing is undesirable in the agitation of biological systems?", "opta": "The collision between the cells, impeller and air bubbles will lead to cell damage", "optb": "Poor mixing despite the use of high stirrer speeds", "optc": "Mixing will not be in the turbulent region", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The rate limiting step in the movement of oxygen from the gas phase in a bubble to the cell is the movement of oxygen molecules through", "opta": "gas-liquid interface", "optb": "bubble boundary layer", "optc": "bulk liquid", "optd": "gas phase", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Penetration theory assumes that turbulent eddies travel from the bulk of the phase to the interface where they remain constant for a constant exposure time (te). The model correlating KL, mass transfer coefficient and DAB, diffusivity can be expressed as", "opta": "KL = 2(DAB/\u03c0te)0.25", "optb": "KL = 2(DAB/\u03c0te)0.5", "optc": "KL = 2(DAB/\u03c0te)0.75", "optd": "KL = 2(DAB/\u03c0te)", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The oxygen uptake requirements of a microbial population is characterized by the following parameters: \u03bcm = 0.2 h-1, K0 = 0.2 mg O2.l-1, Y0 = 0.5 mg dry weight/mg O2 and C0,crit=0.8 mg.l-1 The required concentration of cells is 1000 mg.l-1 and the saturation oxygen concentration of the medium is 5.8 mg.l-1. The required KLa must be greater than", "opta": "64 h-1", "optb": "32 h-1", "optc": "16 h-1", "optd": "8h-1", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which have the maximum resistance while transferring carbon dioxide from the bulk liquid to an air bubble?", "opta": "Moving through the gas liquid interface", "optb": "Moving through the bubble boundary layer", "optc": "Moving across the cell membrane", "optd": "Moving through the bulk liquid", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If liquid density and viscosity remains constant, then the Reynolds number in a stirred tank reactor will vary with the", "opta": "impeller diameter", "optb": "square root of the impeller diameter", "optc": "square of the impeller diameter", "optd": "cube of the impeller diameter", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the ratio of depth of liquid in vessel to the diameter of tank (H:Dt)?", "opta": "1 : 1", "optb": "2 : 1", "optc": "4 : 1", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Radial flow impellers", "opta": "provide high shear conditions for breaking up bubbles", "optb": "direct flow towards the walls of the reactor", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "provide low shear conditions and are suited for use in shear sensitive procesess", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Transient flow range of mixing speed is obtained for", "opta": "Rei<10", "optb": "10<Rei<104", "optc": "Rei&gt10;4", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A typical ceiling fan would be best described as a(n)", "opta": "radial flow impeller", "optb": "axial flow impeller", "optc": "intermig impeller", "optd": "Rushton turbine", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the ratio of diameter of impeller to the diameter of tank (Da:Dt)?", "opta": "1 : 3", "optb": "2 : 1", "optc": "4 : 1", "optd": "1 : 5", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The reason of using a flat disk in a Turbine is", "opta": "to create high shear conditions", "optb": "to break up bubbles more efficiently than the impeller blades", "optc": "to ensure that the bulk of the energy consumption occurs at the blades", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not considered among the three best-known theories of interphase mass transfer?", "opta": "two-film theory", "optb": "penetration theory", "optc": "surface renewal theory", "optd": "Calderbank and Moo-Young theory", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is most likely to cause an increase in the rate of oxygen transfer into a particular aerated fermentation system?", "opta": "Addition of antifoams", "optb": "Increase in temperature", "optc": "Increase in stirrer speed", "optd": "Both (a) and (b)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "At 25\u00b0C, the saturation concentration of oxygen in water is 1.26 mmol/l and the partial pressure of oxygen is 1 atm. The Henry's law constant will be", "opta": "0.793atml/mmol", "optb": "0.207atml/mmol", "optc": "1.26 atml/mmol", "optd": "8.74 atml/mmol", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Gas hold up, characterizing the hydrodynamics in a fermenter, mainly depends on the", "opta": "superficial gas velocity", "optb": "power consumption", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "gas concentration", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Turbine impeller consists of flat impeller blades with", "opta": "a vertical pitch welded directly to the shaft", "optb": "a angled pitch welded directly to the shaft", "optc": "a vertical pitch welded to a horizontal disk", "optd": "a angled pitch welded to a horizontal disk", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An aerated bioreactor will increase oxygen transfer rates with the addition of detergents because it", "opta": "enhances bubble coalescence", "optb": "causes bubbles to expand", "optc": "discourages bubble coalescence", "optd": "increases the surface tension of the liquid", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Vortexing in stirred tank reactors can be prevented by", "opta": "installing baffles in the reactor", "optb": "shifting the impeller to an off-centre position", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "using axial flow impellers", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following would be best described as an axial flow impeller?", "opta": "An impeller with blades pitched at 45\u00b0 to the vertical", "optb": "An impeller which directs liquid flow towards the base of the reactor", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "An impeller with blades pitched at 75\u00b0 to the vertical", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Henry's law relates", "opta": "the partial pressure of oxygen and the saturation concentration of oxygen in the liquid", "optb": "the oxygen transfer rate and the bubble size", "optc": "the oxygen transfer rate and the temperature", "optd": "the oxygen transfer rate to the partial pressure of oxygen in the liquid", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Power number is ratio of", "opta": "imposed forced to intertial force", "optb": "bouyant force to inertial force", "optc": "gravitation force to inertial force", "optd": "imposed force to gravitational force", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The volume of liquid (VL) in a cylindrical reactor can be calculated from the liquid height (HL) and tank diameter (Dt) using the following equation", "opta": "VL = 4/3 x \u03c0 x HL x Dt3/8", "optb": "VL= HL x \u03c0 x Dt2/4", "optc": "VL= HL x \u03c0 x Dt2", "optd": "VL = 4 x \u03c0 x Dt2", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The average fractional gas hold up (H) can be given as  (where Zf and Zl are the level of aerated and clear liquid respectively)", "opta": "H = (Zf-Zl)/Zf", "optb": "H = Zf/Zl", "optc": "H = Zf/ZfZl", "optd": "H =(Zf+Zl)/Zf", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following(s) is/are non-mechanically agitated reactors?", "opta": "Stirrer tank reactor", "optb": "Bubble column", "optc": "Air lift reactor", "optd": "Both   (b) and (c)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following best explains the reasons for using axial flow impellers in crystallization and precipitation reactions?", "opta": "Crystal and precipitates are not too small, so as to ensure easy separation of the solids from the mother liquor", "optb": "Crystals and precipitates are thoroughly broken down, so as to ensure easy separation of the solids from the mother liquor", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "Axial flow impellers provide low shear, energy efficient mixing conditions", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following will have the highest surface area available for oxygen transfer?", "opta": "A shake flask", "optb": "A standing test tube", "optc": "A non-sparged stirred tank reactor agitated at 400 rpm", "optd": "A sparged stirred tank reactor agitated at 400 rpm", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A flooded impeller will lead to poor oxygen transfer rates because", "opta": "bubbles tend to coalesce under the impeller", "optb": "bubbles tend to break down too rapidly under high shear conditions", "optc": "bubbles tend to move too quickly through the bulk liquid", "optd": "the cells clog up the surface of the bubble", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Power consumption by agitation is", "opta": "a function of physical properties", "optb": "a function of operating conditions", "optc": "a function of vessel and impeller geometry", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following impellers will provide radial flow?", "opta": "Paddles", "optb": "Flat blade turbines", "optc": "Disk flat blade turbines", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When liquid is pumped through cooling coil in a stirred tank reactor to cool. Which of the following is not correct?", "opta": "If the stirrer speed is increased, the rate will be faster", "optb": "Baffles in the tank will increase the rate of cooling", "optc": "Faster cooling rates at a slower rate of pumping", "optd": "Faster cooling rates at a faster rate of pumping", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}